Guide to the H.D. Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Papers, 1911-63; Series III; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  - Financial Papers
    - Royalty statements: Macmillan and Company, 1949, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1217)
    - Royalty statements: Oxford University Press, 1944-48 (Box 48, Folder 1218)
    - Royalty statements: Society of Authors, 1956-61 (Box 48, Folder 1219)
    - Statements: American, 1928-53 (Box 48, Folder 1220)
    - Statements: European, 1933-61 (Box 48, Folder 1221)
  - Genealogical notes
    - Doolittle family, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1222)
    - Notes - miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1223)
  - Marriage registration, 1913, 1937 (Box 49, Folder 1224)
  - Medical records
    - Miscellaneous, 1939-45 (Box 49, Folder 1225)
    - Privat-Nerven Klinik, 1957-60 (Box 49, Folder 1226)
  - Memorabilia, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1227)
  - Musical adaptions from H.D.'s poems: programs, 1943-56 (Box 49, Folder 1228)
  - Passports, 1915-56 (Box 49, Folder 1229-30)
  - Permissions requests, 1941 (Box 49, Folder 1231)
  - Postcards
    - Art: American and British (Box 49, Folder 1232)
    - Art: Classical, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1233)
    - Art: Egyptian, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1234)
    - Art: European, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1235)
    - England (Box 49, Folder 1236)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1237)
    - United States: general, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1238)
    - United States: Connecticut, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1239)
    - United States: Pennsylvania, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1240)
  - Powers of attorney, 1934-38 (Box 49, Folder 1241)
  - Scrapbook
    See: Oversize, Box 62, folder 1430
  - Silhouettes: Lotte Reiniger, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1242)
  - Statement Concerning Ezra Pound by the Citizens of Rapallo, Italy, 1948 (Box 49, Folder 1243)
  - Stationery, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1244)
  - Wills, 1948-63 (Box 49, Folder 1245)
- Subject Files, 1913-63; Series IV; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  Series IV, Subject Files, consists of two boxes of pamphlets and clippings arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Aldington, Richard, 1913-62 (Box 50, Folder 1246)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 1247)
  - Art (Box 50, Folder 1248)
  - The Ballet of Lithuania, 1935, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1249)
  - Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, 1936-56, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1250-51)
  - Borderline, 1930, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1252)
  - Bryher, 1960, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1253)
  - Bryn Mawr, 1951-61 (Box 50, Folder 1254)
  - Butler, E. M. (Eliza Marian), 1949-59, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1255)
  - D'Auria, Gemma, 1950-53 (Box 50, Folder 1256)
  - Davidson, Gustav, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 1257)
  - Doolittle family, 1918 (Box 50, Folder 1258)
  - Douglas, Norman, 1952 (Box 50, Folder 1259)
  - Dowding, Hugh Caswell Tremenheere, Sir, 1957, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1260)
  - Durand, Lionel, 1960-61 (Box 50, Folder 1261)
  - Eliot, T. sS., 1948, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1262)
  - Ellerman, Hannah Glover, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1263)
  - Ellis, Havelock, 1921-39 (Box 50, Folder 1264)
  - English literature, 20th century, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1265)
  - Ford, Ford Madox, 1950 (Box 50, Folder 1266)
  - Freud, Sigmund, 1935-61, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1267-68)
    See also: Oversize, Box 62, folder 1428
  - Gaudier-Brzeska, Henri, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 1269)
  - Guest, Leslie Haden, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 1270)
  - Hesse, Hermann, 1947, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1271)
  - Howard, Hildegarde, 1951-57 (Box 50, Folder 1272)
  - Huxley, Aldous, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1273)
  - Lawrence, D. H., 1960 (Box 50, Folder 1274)
  - Leeuw, J. J. van der, 1934 (Box 50, Folder 1275)
  - Leslie, Doris, 1928 (Box 50, Folder 1276)
  - McAlmon, Robert, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1277)
  - Martinelli, Sheri, 1960-63 (Box 50, Folder 1278)
  - Miscellaneous, 1943-75, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1279)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1955 (Box 50, Folder 1280)
  - Moravians, 1945, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1281)
  - Motion pictures, 1929 (Box 50, Folder 1282)
  - Olympic decathalon, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 1283)
  - Parkham, Nellie E., 1934-45 (Box 50, Folder 1284)
  - Poetry readings, 1943 (Box 51, Folder 1285-86)
  - The Poetry Society of America, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 1287)
  - Pound, Ezra, 1933-59 (Box 51, Folder 1288)
  - Pre-Raphaelites, 1948 (Box 51, Folder 1289)
  - Privat-Nerven Klinik, 1957, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1290)
  - Reiniger, Lotte, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 1291)
  - Reviews: miscellaneous, 1925-58, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1292)
  - Richardson, Dorothy, 1931-50 (Box 51, Folder 1293)
  - Royal family, British: clippings
    See: Oversize, Box 62, folder 1429
  - Shakespeare, William, 1960, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1294)
  - Shakespeare and Company, 1959, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1295)
  - Sitwell, Edith, Dame, 1952, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1296)
  - Whitall, James, 1935, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1297)
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 1298)
  - Windsor, House of, 1923-50 (Box 51, Folder 1299)
  - Wolle, Francis, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 1300)
  - Wolle, J. Fred, 1933, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1301)
  - Wolle, Jennie Stryker, 1934 [?] (Box 51, Folder 1302)
  - World War II, 1943-45 (Box 51, Folder 1303)
  - Wulfing, Sulamith, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1304)
- Photographs, 1887-1960; Series V; 1.75; (4 boxes)
  Series V, Photographs, consists of four boxes of photographs arranged alphabetically by individual or subject.
  - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1305)
  - Unidentified glass plate, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1306)
  - Aldington, Catherine, 1946-57, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1307)
  - Aldington, Richard [group I], 1929-59, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1308)
  - Aldington, Richard [group II], 1916-42, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1309-11)
  - Allison, Henry, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1312)
  - Beach, Sylvia, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1313)
  - Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1314)
  - Borderline [film]: production, 1929 (Box 52, Folder 1315)
  - Borderline [film]: production stills, 1929 (Box 52, Folder 1316-17)
  - Bryher, 1920-60 [?] (Box 52, Folder 1318)
  - Bryn Mawr College, 1960 (Box 52, Folder 1319)
  - Butler, E. M. (Eliza Marian), n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1320)
  - Cole, M. D., 1935 (Box 52, Folder 1321)
  - Doolittle, Charles Leander, ca. 1900, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1322)
  - Doolittle, Edith, 1883 (Box 52, Folder 1323)
  - Doolittle, Eric, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1324)
  - Doolittle, Harold, 1942-44, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1325)
  - Doolittle, Helen Wolle, 1873-1924, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1326)
  - Doolittle, Melvin, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1327)
  - Duncan, Robert Edward, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1328)
  - Ellis, Havelock, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1329)
  - Frere, Philip, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1329a)
  - Freud, Sigmund (Box 53, Folder 1330)
  - Gunther, Alfred, 1955 (Box 53, Folder 1331)
  - H.D., 1887-1929 (Box 53, Folder 1332-54)
    See also: Oversize, Box 62, folder 1428; Related Papers, Box 63, folder 1431
  - H.D., 1930-61 (Box 54, Folder 1355-69)
  - H.D.: deathmask, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1370)
  - Herring, Robert, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1371)
  - Hesse, Hermann, 1950-51 (Box 54, Folder 1372)
  - Heydt, Erich, 1956, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1373)
  - Howard, Hattie, 1945 (Box 54, Folder 1374)
  - Jordan, Viola, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1375)
  - Kenwin. Burier, Switzerland (Box 54, Folder 1376)
  - Long, Doris, 1921, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1377)
  - Lyons, Islay [photographs by], n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1378)
  - McAlmon, Robert, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1379)
  - Macpherson, Kenneth, 1927-50, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1380)
  - Martinelli, Sheri, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 1381)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1382)
  - Monkey's Moon [film], n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1383)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 1384)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1959-60, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1385)
  - Pound, Ezra (Box 54, Folder 1386)
  - Pratt, Margaret Snively, 1959 (Box 54, Folder 1387)
  - Rachewiltz, Mary de [and family] (Box 55, Folder 1388)
  - Reiniger, Lotte, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1389)
  - Rossetti, William Michael, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1390)
  - San Gimignano, Italy, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1391)
  - Schaffner, Perdita, 1937-61, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1392-93)
  - Schmideberg, Walter and Melitta (Box 55, Folder 1394)
  - [Scilly Islands] (Box 55, Folder 1395)
  - Scops Owl, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1396)
  - Street, Florence Prince [and family] (Box 55, Folder 1397)
  - Trenoweth [St. Keverne, Cornwall], [1944] (Box 55, Folder 1398)
  - Upper Darby, Pennsylvania, 1907, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1399)
  - Wolle, Francis, 1890, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1400)
- Additional Papers, 1915-60; Series VI; 3.5; (6 boxes)
  Series IV, Additional Papers, consists of one box of alphabetically arranged photocopies of correspondence not owned by Yale. This material is not available for photocopying. In addition, there are five boxes of indexes relating to the collection.
  - CORRESPONDENCE NOT OWNED BY YALE
    - Aldington, Richard, to Amy Lowell, 1961 (Box 56, Folder 1401)
    - Bryher to:
      - Richard Aldington, 1929 (Box 56, Folder 1402)
      - Francis Wolle, 1949 (Box 56, Folder 1403)
    - H.D. to:
      - Conrad Aiken, [192?] (Box 56, Folder 1404)
      - Richard Aldington, 1937-61 (Box 56, Folder 1405-11)
      - Harold P. Collins, 1925-40 (Box 56, Folder 1412)
      - Glen Hughes, 1929 (Box 56, Folder 1413)
      - Molly Hughes, 1942-47 (Box 56, Folder 1414)
      - Amy Lowell, 1914-25 (Box 56, Folder 1415-16)
      - Edward Nehls, [195?] (Box 56, Folder 1417)
      - Charles Norman, 1959-60 (Box 56, Folder 1418)
      - Peter Russell, 1950 (Box 56, Folder 1419)
      - Edith Sitwell, 1949-54 (Box 56, Folder 1420)
      - Osbert Sitwell, 1943 (Box 56, Folder 1421)
      - Francis Wolle, 1929-57 (Box 56, Folder 1422)
  - INDEXES
    - Titles and first lines of writings (Box 57, Folder 1423)
    - First lines to published works, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1424)
    - H.D.'s library, n.d. (Box 59a, Folder 1425)
    - Photocopies of notes on the books in H.D.'s library (Box 59b, Folder 1425a)
      Notes made by Susan Stanford Friedman in 1969
    - Alphabetical/cross reference, Series I-II, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1426)
    - Alphabetical/cross reference, Series II-V, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1427)
- Oversize, n.d.
  - Freud, Sigmund: etching and clipping (Box 62, Folder 1428)
  - Royal family, British: clippings, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 1429)
  - Scrapbook containing photographs of H. D., Kenneth Mapherson, Bryher, and others (Box 62, Folder 1430)
  - Writings
    - "The Griffin of Temple Bar: printed version, 1912 (Box 62, Folder 1430a)
    - "Lady Leister:" printed version, 1911 (Box 62, Folder 1430b)
    - Eastwood, Thomas
      - "At Baia" by H.D., music by Thomas Eastwood, holograph, [1956?] (Box 62, Folder 1430c)
    - Elkus, Jonathan
      - "Triptych" by H.D. music by Jonathan Elkus, holograph, photocopy, 1965 (Box 62, Folder 1430)
- Related Papers, 1917-1970; 0.5; (1 box)
  Box 63, Related Papers, consists of papers added to the collection since it was first processed. The material is arranged in series order.
  - Photographs
    - Portraits of H.D., ca. 1917 (Box 63, Folder 1431)
  - Writings
    - Bid Me to Live: uncorrected proofs, 1960 (Box 63, Folder 1432)
    - "Sagesse:"
      - "The Shell:" printed version, 1969 (Box 63, Folder 1433)
    - "Leda:" printed version, 1919 (Box 63, Folder 1434)
    - "Two Poems"
      - "Choragus and Helen:" printed version, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 1435)
    - Tribute to the Angels: galley proofs, uncorrected, 1944 (Box 63, Folder 1436)
    - Tribute to Freud:
      - "Écrit sur le mur:" [french translation] printed version, 1970 (Box 63, Folder 1437)
    - "A Letter from England:" printed (Box 63, Folder 1438)
      - version., 1970
    - "Prose Chorus:" printed version, 1925 (Box 63, Folder 1439)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes
      - "Billy Budd: The King's Yarn:" printed version, 1951 (Box 63, Folder 1440)
    - White, Eric Walter
      - "Early Theatrical Performances of Purcell's Opera:" printed version, 1959 (Box 63, Folder 1441)
    - Friedman, Susan Stanford
      - "Mythology, Psychoanalysis, and the Occult in the late poetry of H.D.," photocopy inscribed to Norman Holmes Pearson, 1973 (Box 64, Folder 1442-1446)
  - Needlepoint canvases and related materials
    Includes two finished and two unfinished needlepoint canvases made by H.D., likely during the Blitz, and possibly completed at a later date. Also included are sewing notions and wool yarn fragments for various needlepoint projects. Some tapestries are made from commercially printed patterns.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Gift of the Schaffner Family Foundation, 2017.
    Appraisal
    Four items originally housed with the needlepoint canvases were removed from the collection at the request of the curator and returned to the donor. In consultation with the donor, these items were deemed unrelated to the needlepoint canvases donated by the Schaffner Family Foundation. Photographs of these items are included in the collection.
    - Framed needlepoint canvas of a fruit grove with animals, circa 1940-1949; 43 x 95 cm, in frame 54 x 106 cm (Box 66 (Art))
    - Needlepoint canvas of Sanctus Hubertus, circa 1940-1949; Image 40 x 58 cm, on canvas mesh 60 x 78 cm (Box 67)
    - Needlepoint canvas of a pastoral scene, unfinished, circa 1940-1949; Image 54 x 129 cm, on canvas mesh 70 x 152 cm (Box 67)
    - Needlepoint canvas of woodland scene on dark background, unfinished, circa 1940-1949; Image 32 x 44 cm, on canvas mesh 47 x 55 cm (Box 67)
      Includes two blunt needlepoint needles threaded into the fabric, one with green yarn, and one with dark brown yarn.
    - Sewing and needlework notions, undated (Box 68)
      Includes thread, buttons and clasps, thimble, embroidered handkerchief, calico fragments, and a canvas and cotton needle case in the shape of a book.
    - Needlepoint yarn fragments for various projects, undated
      - 3rd Cluny Museum panel, undated (Box 69)
      - Vienna Long Panel, undated (Box 69)
      - Wool left from St. Hubertus and Perdita's Bag, undated (Box 69)
      - Unidentified needlepoint yarn fragments, undated (Box 69)
    - Photographs of unrelated material originally housed with needlepoint canvases, 2018-04-05 (Box 64, Folder 1446a)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21; (1 box)
  - Glass negatives from Box 63, Folder 1431 (Box 65, Folder 1447)